
var quiz = {
  "JS": [
  {
  "id": 1,
  "question": "Number of primitive data types in Java are?",
  "options": [
  {
  "a": "6",
  "b": "7",
  "c": "8",
  "d": "9"
  }
  ],
  "answer": "8",
  "score": 0,
  "status": ""
  },
  {
  "id": 2,
  "question": "When an array is passed to a method, what does the method receive?",
  "options": [
  {
  "a": "The reference of the array",
  "b": "A copy of the array",
  "c": "Length of the array",
  "d": "A copy of first element"
  }
  ],
  "answer": "The reference of the array",
  "score": 0,
  "status": ""
  },
  {
  "id": 3,
  "question": "Arrays in java are-",
  "options": [
  {
  "a": "objects",
  "b": "object references",
  "c": "primitive data types",
  "d": "none"
  }
  ],
  "answer": "objects",
  "score": 0,
  "status": ""
  },
  {
  "id": 4,
  "question": "Arrays in java are-",
  "options": [
  {
  "a": "A package is a collection of editing tools",
  "b": "A package is a collection of classes",
  "c": "A package is a collection of classes and interfaces",
  "b": "A package is a collection of interfaces"
  }
  ],
  "answer": "A package is a collection of classes and interfaces",
  "score": 0,
  "status": ""
  },
  {
  "id": 5,
  "question": "Identify the keyword among the following that makes a variable belong to a class,rather than being defined for each instance of the class.",
  "options": [
  {
  "a": "final",
  "b": "static",
  "c": "volatile",
  "d": "abstract",
  }
  ],
  "answer": "static",
  "score": 0,
  "status": ""
  },
  {
  "id": 6,
  "question": "compareTo() returns",
  "options": [
  {
  "a": "True",
  "b": "False",
  "c": "An int value",
  "d": "None"
  }
  ],
  "answer": "An int value",
  "score": 0,
  "status": ""
  },
  {
  "id": 7,
  "question": "To which of the following does the class string belong to.",
  "options": [
  {
  "a": "java.lang",
  "b": "java.awt",
  "c": "java.applet",
  "d": "java.string"
  }
  ],
  "answer": "java.lang",
  "score": 0,
  "status": ""
  },
  {
  "id": 8,
  "question": "Total constructor string class have?",
  "options": [
  {
  "a": "3",
  "b": "7",
  "c": "13",
  "d": "20",
  }
  ],
  "answer": "13",
  "score": 0,
  "status": ""
  },
  {
  "id": 9,
  "question": "Identify the return type of a method that does not return any value.",
  "options": [
  {
  "a": "int",
  "b": "void",
  "c": "double",
  "d": "none"
  }
  ],
  "answer": "void",
  "score": 0,
  "status": ""
  },
  {
  "id": 10,
  "question": "Output of Math.floor(3.6)?",
  "options": [
  {
  "a": "3",
  "b": "4",
  "c": "3.0",
  "d": "4.0",
  }
  ],
  "answer": "3.0",
  "score": 0,
  "status": ""
  },
  {
  "id": 11,
  "question": "Identify the modifier which cannot be used for constructor.",
  "options": [
  {
  "a": "public",
  "b": "protected",
  "c": "private",
  "d": "static"
  }
  ],
  "answer": "static",
  "score": 0,
  "status": ""
  },
  {
  "id": 12,
  "question": "When is the finalize() method called?",
  "options": [
  {
  "a": "Before garbage collection",
  "b": "Before an object goes out of scope",
  "c": "Before a variable goes out of scope",
  "d": "None"
  }
  ],
  "answer": "Before garbage collection",
  "score": 0,
  "status": ""
  },
  {
  "id": 13,
  "question": "What is the implicit return type of constructor?",
  "options": [
  {
  "a": "Void",
  "b": "None",
  "c": "No return type",
  "d": "A class object in which it is defined"
  }
  ],
  "answer": "A class object in which it is defined",
  "score": 0,
  "status": ""
  },
  {
  "id": 14,
  "question": "What is the variables declared in a class for the use of all methods of the class called?",
  "options": [
  {
  "a": "Intance variables",
  "b": "Object",
  "c": "Reference variable",
  "d": "None"
  }
  ],
  "answer": "Intance variable",
  "score": 0,
  "status": ""
  },
  {
  "id": 15,
  "question": "What is Runnable?",
  "options": [
  {
  "a": "Abstract class",
  "b": "Interface",
  "c": "Class",
  "d": "Method"
  }
  ],
  "answer": "Interface",
  "score": 0,
  "status": ""
  },
  {
  "id": 16,
  "question": "Exception created by try block is caught in which block",
  "options": [
  {
  "a": "catch",
  "b": "throw",
  "c": "final",
  "d": "none"
  }
  ],
  "answer": "catch",
  "score": 0,
  "status": ""
  },
  {
  "id": 17,
  "question": "Where is System class defined?",
  "options": [
  {
  "a": "java.lang.package",
  "b": "java.util.package",
  "c": "java.io.package",
  "d": "None"
  }
  ],
  "answer": "java.lang.package",
  "score": 0,
  "status": ""
  },
  {
  "id": 18,
  "question": "What does the operator >>>> do?",
  "options": [
  {
  "a": "Right shift operator",
  "b": "Left shift operator",
  "c": "Zero fill right shift",
  "d": "Zero fill left shift"
  }
  ],
  "answer": "Zero fill right shift",
  "score": 0,
  "status": ""
  },
  {
  "id": 19,
  "question": "Java is the same as Javascript.",
  "options": [
  {
  "a": "true",
  "b": "false"
  }
  ],
  "answer": "false",
  "score": 0,
  "status": ""
  },
  {
  "id": 20,
  "question": "Identify the incorrect Java feature.",
  "options": [
  {
  "a": "Dynamic",
  "b": "Architectural neural",
  "c": "Object oriented",
  "d": "Use of pointers"
  }
  ],
  "answer": "Use of pointers",
  "score": 0,
  "status": ""
  },
  {
  "id": 21,
  "question": "Which of the following statements are true about finalize() method?",
  "options": [
  {
  "a": "it can be called zero or one times",
  "b": "it can be called zero or more times",
  "c": "it can be called one or more time",
  "d": "it can be called exactly once"
  }
  ],
  "answer": "it can be called zero or one times",
  "score": 0,
  "status": ""
  },
  {
  "id": 22,
  "question": "Which of the following exception is thrown when divided by zero statement is executed?",
  "options": [
  {
  "a": "NullPointerException",
  "b": "NumberFormatException",
  "c": "ArthmeticException",
  "d": "None"
  }
  ],
  "answer": "ArthmeticException",
  "score": 0,
  "status": ""
  },
  {
  "id": 23,
  "question": "Identify the interface which is used to declare core methods in java?",
  "options": [
  {
  "a": "set",
  "b": "collection",
  "c": "comparator",
  "d": "EventListner"
  }
  ],
  "answer": "collection",
  "score": 0,
  "status": ""
  },
  {
  "id": 24,
  "question": "Which of the following is used to find and fix bugs in the program?",
  "options": [
  {
  "a": "JDB",
  "b": "JVM",
  "c": "JDK",
  "D": "JRE"
  }
  ],
  "answer": "JDB",
  "score": 0,
  "status": ""
  },
  {
  "id": 25,
  "question": "Where does the system stores parameters and local variables whenever a method is invoked?",
  "options": [
  {
  "a": "Heap",
  "b": "Stack",
  "c": "Tree",
  "d": "Array"
  }
  ],
  "answer": "Stack",
  "score": 0,
  "status": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 26,
    "question": "When is the object created with new keyword?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Depends on the code",
    "b": "At run time",
    "c": "At compile Time",
    "d": "None"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "At run time",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
      "id": 27,
      "question": " What is the return type of the hashCode() method in the Object class?",
      "options": [
      {
      "a": "void",
      "b": "int",
      "c": "long",
      "d": "object"
      }
      ],
      "answer": "int",
      "score": 0,
      "status": ""
      },
      {
        "id": 28,
        "question": "What does the expression float a = 35 / 0 return?",
        "options": [
        {
        "a": "Infinity",
        "b": "0",
        "c": "Not a number",
        "d": "run time exception"
        }
        ],
        "answer": "Infinity",
        "score": 0,
        "status": ""
        },
        {
          "id": 29,
          "question": " Which of the following tool is used to generate API documentation in HTML format from doc comments in source code?",
          "options": [
          {
          "a": "javap tool",
          "b": "javaw command",
          "c": "javadoc tool",
          "d": "javah command"
          }
          ],
          "answer": "javadoc tool",
          "score": 0,
          "status": ""
          },
          {
            "id": 30,
            "question": "Which of the following is true about the anonymous inner class?",
            "options": [
            {
            "a": "It has only methods",
            "b": "It has no class name",
            "c": "It has a fixed class name",
            "d": "Objects can't be created"
            }
            ],
            "answer": "It has no class name",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
            },
            {
              "id": 31,
              "question": "Which method of the Class.class is used to determine the name of a class represented by the class object as a String?",
              "options": [
              {
              "a": "intern()",
              "b": "getClass()",
              "c": "getName()",
              "d": "toString()"
              }
              ],
              "answer": "getName()",
              "score": 0,
              "status": ""
              },
              {
                "id": 32,
                "question": "Which package contains the Random class?",
                "options": [
                {
                "a": "java.util package",
                "b": "java.lang package",
                "c": "java.awt package",
                "d": "java.io package"
                }
                ],
                "answer": "java.util package",
                "score": 0,
                "status": ""
                },
                {
                  "id": 33,
                  "question": "What do you mean by nameless objects?",
                  "options": [
                  {
                  "a": "An object of a superclass created in the subclass.",
                  "b": "An object created by using the new keyword.",
                  "c": "An object without having any name but having a reference",
                  "d": "An object that has no reference."
                  }
                  ],
                  "answer": "An object that has no reference.",
                  "score": 0,
                  "status": ""
                  },
                  {
                    "id": 34,
                    "question": "In which process, a local variable has the same name as one of the instance variables?",
                    "options": [
                    {
                    "a": "Multi Threading",
                    "b": "Abstraction",
                    "c": "serialization",
                    "d": "variable shadowing"
                    }
                    ],
                    "answer": "variable shadowing",
                    "score": 0,
                    "status": ""
                    },
                    {
                      "id": 35,
                      "question": "Which of the following option leads to the portability and security of Java?",
                      "options": [
                      {
                      "a": "Dynamic binding between objects",
                      "b": "Bytecode is executed by JVM",
                      "c": "Use of exception handling",
                      "d": "The applet makes the Java code secure and portable"
                      }
                      ],
                      "answer": "Bytecode is executed by JVM",
                      "score": 0,
                      "status": ""
                      },
                      {
                        "id": 36,
                        "question": "Which of the following is a valid long literal?",
                        "options": [
                        {
                        "a": "0xnf029L",
                        "b": "L990023",
                        "c": "ABH8097",
                        "d": "904423"
                        }
                        ],
                        "answer": "0xnf029L",
                        "score": 0,
                        "status": ""
                        },
                        {
                          "id": 37,
                          "question": "Which of the following is true about the anonymous inner class?",
                          "options": [
                          {
                          "a": "It has a fixed class name",
                          "b": "It has no class name",
                          "c": "It has only methods",
                          "d": "Objects can't be created"
                          }
                          ],
                          "answer": "It has no class name",
                          "score": 0,
                          "status": ""
                          },
                          {
                            "id": 38,
                            "question": " An interface with no fields or methods is known as a ______.",
                            "options": [
                            {
                            "a": "CharSequence Interface",
                            "b": "Abstract Interface",
                            "c": "Marker Interface",
                            "d": "Runnable Interface"
                            }
                            ],
                            "answer": "Marker Interface",
                            "score": 0,
                            "status": ""
                            },
                            {
                              "id": 39,
                              "question": "In which memory a String is stored, when we create a string using new operator?",
                              "options": [
                              {
                              "a": "String memory",
                              "b": "Heap memory",
                              "c": "Stack",
                              "d": "Random storage space"
                              }
                              ],
                              "answer": "Heap Memory",
                              "score": 0,
                              "status": ""
                              },
                              {
                                "id": 40,
                                "question": "Which of the following is an immediate subclass of the Panel class?",
                                "options": [
                                {
                                "a": "Dialog class",
                                "b": "Frame class",
                                "c": "Applet class",
                                "d": "Window class"
                                }
                                ],
                                "answer": "Applet class",
                                "score": 0,
                                "status": ""
                                },
                                {
                                  "id": 41,
                                  "question": "Which of these classes are the direct subclasses of the Throwable class?",
                                  "options": [
                                  {
                                  "a": "IOException and VirtualMachineError class",
                                  "b": "Exception and VirtualMachineError class",
                                  "c": "RuntimeException and Error class",
                                  "d": "Error and Exception class"
                                  }
                                  ],
                                  "answer": "Error And Exception class",
                                  "score": 0,
                                  "status": ""
                                  },
                                  {
                                    "id": 42,
                                    "question": "Which of the following is a valid long literal?",
                                    "options": [
                                    {
                                    "a": "Exceptions occur in chains with discarding the debugging information",
                                    "b": "An exception caused by other exceptions",
                                    "c": "Exceptions occurred by the VirtualMachineError",
                                    "d": "None of the above"
                                    }
                                    ],
                                    "answer": "An exception caused by other exceptions",
                                    "score": 0,
                                    "status": ""
                                    },
                                    {
                                      "id": 43,
                                      "question": "Which of the following is a marker interface?",
                                      "options": [
                                      {
                                      "a": "Remote interface",
                                      "b": "Result interface",
                                      "c": "Readable interface",
                                      "d": "Runnable interface"
                                      }
                                      ],
                                      "answer": "Remote Interface",
                                      "score": 0,
                                      "status": ""
                                      },
                                      {
                                        "id": 44,
                                        "question": " What is the use of the intern() method??",
                                        "options": [
                                        {
                                        "a": "It modifies the existing string in the database",
                                        "b": "It creates a new string in the database",
                                        "c": "None of the above",
                                        "d": "It returns the existing string from memory"
                                        }
                                        ],
                                        "answer": "It returns the existing string from memory",
                                        "score": 0,
                                        "status": ""
                                        },
                                        {
                                          "id": 45,
                                          "question": "In java, jar stands for_____.",
                                          "options": [
                                          {
                                          "a": "Java Application Runner",
                                          "b": "None of the option",
                                          "c": "Java Archive Runner",
                                          "d": "Java Application Resource"
                                          }
                                          ],
                                          "answer": "None of option",
                                          "score": 0,
                                          "status": ""
                                          },
                                          {
                                            "id": 46,
                                            "question": " Which of the following is a reserved keyword in Java?",
                                            "options": [
                                            {
                                            "a": "main",
                                            "b": "strictfp",
                                            "c": "object",
                                            "d": "system"
                                            }
                                            ],
                                            "answer": "strictfp",
                                            "score": 0,
                                            "status": ""
                                            },
                                            {
                                              "id": 47,
                                              "question": "Which keyword is used for accessing the features of a package?",
                                              "options": [
                                              {
                                              "a": "export",
                                              "b": "import",
                                              "c": "package",
                                              "d": "extends"
                                              }
                                              ],
                                              "answer": "import",
                                              "score": 0,
                                              "status": ""
                                              },
                                              {
                                                "id": 48,
                                                "question": "What is the use of \w in regex?",
                                                "options": [
                                                {
                                                "a": "Used for a non-word character",
                                                "b": "Used for a non-whitespace character",
                                                "c": "Used for a word character",
                                                "d": "Used for a whitespace character"
                                                }
                                                ],
                                                "answer": "Used for a word character",
                                                "score": 0,
                                                "status": ""
                                                },
                                                {
                                                  "id": 49,
                                                  "question": "Which of the following is false?",
                                                  "options": [
                                                  {
                                                  "a": "All the classes available in rt.jar is known to the JVM",
                                                  "b": "The rt.jar stands for the runtime jar",
                                                  "c": "It is an optional jar file",
                                                  "d": "It contains all the compiled class files"
                                                  }
                                                  ],
                                                  "answer": "It is an optional jar file",
                                                  "score": 0,
                                                  "status": ""
                                                  },
                                                  {
                                                    "id": 50,
                                                    "question": "What is the initial quantity of the ArrayList list?",
                                                    "options": [
                                                    {
                                                    "a": "100",
                                                    "b": "10",
                                                    "c": "5",
                                                    "d": "0"
                                                    }
                                                    ],
                                                    "answer": "10",
                                                    "score": 0,
                                                    "status": ""
                                                    }







  ]
  }
  var quizApp = function () {
  this.score = 0;
  this.qno = 1;
  this.currentque = 0;
  var totalque = quiz.JS.length;
  this.displayQuiz = function (cque) {
  this.currentque = cque;
  if (this.currentque < totalque) {
  $("#tque").html(totalque);
  $("#previous").attr("disabled", false);
  $("#next").attr("disabled", false);
  $("#qid").html(quiz.JS[this.currentque].id + '.');
  $("#question").html(quiz.JS[this.currentque].question);
  $("#question-options").html("");
  for (var key in quiz.JS[this.currentque].options[0]) {
  if (quiz.JS[this.currentque].options[0].hasOwnProperty(key)) {
  $("#question-options").append(
  "<div class='form-check option-block'>" +
  "<label class='form-check-label'>" +
  "<input type='radio' class='form-check-input' name='option' id='q" + key + "' value='" + quiz.JS[this.currentque].options[0][key] + "'><span id='optionval'>" +
  quiz.JS[this.currentque].options[0][key] +
  "</span></label>"
  );
  }
  }
  }
  if (this.currentque <= 0) {
  $("#previous").attr("disabled", true);
  }
  if (this.currentque >= totalque) {
  $('#next').attr('disabled', true);
  for (var i = 0; i < totalque; i++) {
  this.score = this.score + quiz.JS[i].score;
  }
  return this.showResult(this.score);
  }
  }
  this.showResult = function (scr) {
  $("#result").addClass('result');
  $("#result").html("<h1 class='res-header'>Total Score: &nbsp;" + scr + '/' + totalque + "</h1>");
  for (var j = 0; j < totalque; j++) {
  var res;
  if (quiz.JS[j].score == 0) {
  res = '<span class="wrong">' + quiz.JS[j].score + '</span><i class="fa fa-remove c-wrong"></i>';
  } else {
  res = '<span class="correct">' + quiz.JS[j].score + '</span><i class="fa fa-check c-correct"></i>';
  }
  $("#result").append(
  '<div class="result-question"><span>Q ' + quiz.JS[j].id + '</span> &nbsp;' + quiz.JS[j].question + '</div>' +
  '<div><b>Correct answer:</b> &nbsp;' + quiz.JS[j].answer + '</div>' +
  '<div class="last-row"><b>Score:</b> &nbsp;' + res +
  '</div>'
  );
  }
  }
  this.checkAnswer = function (option) {
  var answer = quiz.JS[this.currentque].answer;
  option = option.replace(/</g, "&lt;") //for <
  option = option.replace(/>/g, "&gt;") //for >
  option = option.replace(/"/g, "&quot;")
  if (option == quiz.JS[this.currentque].answer) {
  if (quiz.JS[this.currentque].score == "") {
  quiz.JS[this.currentque].score = 1;
  quiz.JS[this.currentque].status = "correct";
  }
  } else {
  quiz.JS[this.currentque].status = "wrong";
  }
  }
  this.changeQuestion = function (cque) {
  this.currentque = this.currentque + cque;
  this.displayQuiz(this.currentque);
  }
  }
  var jsq = new quizApp();
  var selectedopt;
  $(document).ready(function () {
  jsq.displayQuiz(0);
  $('#question-options').on('change', 'input[type=radio][name=option]', function (e) {
  //var radio = $(this).find('input:radio');
  $(this).prop("checked", true);
  selectedopt = $(this).val();
  });
  });
  $('#next').click(function (e) {
  e.preventDefault();
  if (selectedopt) {
  jsq.checkAnswer(selectedopt);
  }
  jsq.changeQuestion(1);
  });
  $('#previous').click(function (e) {
  e.preventDefault();
  if (selectedopt) {
  jsq.checkAnswer(selectedopt);
  }
  jsq.changeQuestion(-1);
  });